<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Scribblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://sunilkumarn.github.io/social/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sunilkumarn.github.io/social/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-19T10:50:24+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sunilkumarn.github.io/social/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sunil Kumar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Through the commoner's eye]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunilkumarn.github.io/social/blog/2013/10/12/through-the-commoners-eye/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-12T19:04:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sunilkumarn.github.io/social/blog/2013/10/12/through-the-commoners-eye</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am not quite sure if am ever the right one to pen this down. May be there are better people, the wiser men, the so called feminists, the politicians and even the professionals. However, I write this as a commoner of our nation, born and brought up here, as someone trying to get in touch with the issues that we face as a society.</p>

<p>As a son, brother, lover, husband or a father, as a friend or a colleague, we all love, respect and honour our women. As a citizen of this country, who has enjoyed the unlimited grant of freedom that this nation provides, ofcourse I want our women to be free and move around in the wear they choose and at a time thats convenient for them. I want and wish them to be safe, irrespective of whether its Delhi, Cochin, Cuttack or Imphal, regardless of whether its 2 in the afternoon or past midnight.</p>

<p><strong>Its precaution that matters more than the punishment.</strong></p>

<p>&lsquo;I want our women to be free, and travel safe&rsquo; &ndash; Thats the good part and thats over. Its no longer there. I am sorry if I pulled of the wrong words, but I mean every word of it. I love and fear the lives of the women connected with me, and the many millions who are not. As someone who is still young, I want my ladies to stay with me, healthy and sound, and there fore to be very precise, I would keep communicating with her, try and stop her moving around alone at night, discourage her travel along with people whom she is not cent percent sure about and do keep a track on her where abouts when and where possible. On the flip side <i>I would never give a damn if she and her friends decide to get along and spend nights out in the beaches of pondicherry or Goa</i>. What I do and possibly want to do has nothing to do with a women&rsquo;s freedom, her rightful advocacy to have fun, and to be on par with me and the others who look like me. This is purely out of the love and the fear that a young man has for the women in his life. I believe we are all born with enough logic to figure out a this from that, and its cardinal to remember that life matters more than the moment.</p>

<p>True, we have every right to demand severe punishment, may be model the arabs and the africans for the kind of severity and wildness they have in their system; casteration(chemical or else wise), stone them to death or let the public handle them, and whatever ways we could think off. But then, we are talking about the punishment, the calvary and gehenna still continues for the loved ones. Along with the modification of laws for prosecuting the culprit, the right full measures for preventing such dreadful acts need to be materialized; and with equal priority.</p>

<p><strong>Isn&rsquo;t this connected to a few other stuffs?</strong></p>

<p>Why is that in our nation, we keep asking our girls to be home on time, not to travel late at night, not to attend her best friends marriage if she is in short of company? The answer is pretty simple, we understand that RAPE or molestation against women is not a stand alone challenge that we face as a society. Its just one out of the many connected nodes; the reasons of which are never perplex and hit straight in our eyes. Poverty, lack of proper education right from level one, a system where Co-education is never considered a mandatory to start with, the ceaseless issue of the ridiculous system of outcastes and the workmanships associated with them, lack of adequate security measures, and above all the availability of drugs and alcohol at rates lower than that of meals.</p>

<p>If you are a citizen who has lived the middle class, lower middle class life or even down from there, I hope you get these issues. You don&rsquo;t have to fume out your brains to get connected with this. Infographics tells me that South Africa has got more number of rape cases registered than any other country in the world ( The United States of America would be topping the list in some surveys as well! ). Now, I assume that this has nothing to do with the body and nature of the women out there, its all about the disastrous state of affairs that is well known to all and sundry. Lack of proper food, education and oppression by fellow beings could well and truly bring out the beast in a human, and when catalysed by alcohol could multiplicate and unleash into something as dirty and wild as could possibly happen. Again, even by the slightest of imaginations, this is never an offer of sympathy to those wicked acts. What they did was possibly the most cruel doing on earth and deserve appropriate punishment.</p>

<p><strong>May be, we could do something here!</strong></p>

<p>We do consider ourselves educated. In a nation like ours, it does means a lot to each and every one of us, though never something that we could really boast of because we never had to sweat out for that. Our backgrounds, economical or social made sure that we grew up educated. Our parents and teachers who brought us up ensured that the moral values were infused in us in as much quantity and quality as science and history were taught to us. I still believe there&rsquo;s one big hole left though, and that for me is getting to your know opposite sex right from a childhood stage. Many believe that its high time co-education is considered a mandatory all the way till you complete your high school education. Myself being taught in mixed schools realize and understand the value of an environment where your opposite sex is never a matter of mystery for you.</p>

<p>Our society&rsquo;s perception of woman, and how woman themselves tackle situations is a matter of amplifying concern. I have seen all kinds of posts in social medias, from images and monster graphics to statuses on how each and every one of them would like to take it up with these barbarians. Fuming anger and outrage is most acceptable, but specific posts appears to be more of a mockery and generates disgust. Psuedo emotions always creeps up irritation. It seems like all, all those craps who have had the least respect for women, all those perverts who when offered with the most slender chance dig into a women&rsquo;s body in crowded transports as and where possible and all those wicked minds who associate terms like &lsquo;slut&rsquo; and &lsquo;whore&rsquo; to each and every women they come across, each and every one of them have got a say here. If you have done it in public transports with minds responsive, then what assurance that you won&rsquo;t do it in the dark when smitten up by alcohol?</p>

<p>In a state like Kerala, what honour do you see for women? A girl when seen with her boyfriend was manhandled by the public, a husband and wife were taken to the police station because they decided to have a breathe of fresh air on the beach sides, a women journalist alone at night was reportedly approached by at least 20 men, and what not? Its important to change this mindset to start with, and then may be we could sort out measures on what needs to be done with the ones caught red handed.</p>

<pre><code>                                            -   -   -       
</code></pre>

<p>Protests, marches and joint prayers in different corners of our nation ensure that we as a nation has not hit the mariana trench. May this be a collective effort which would bring in fruitful results, whether its about identifying the root causes, strengthening security measures and modifying the laws to enhance the mode of punishment. This requires the strength and support of each and every educated civilian in this nation. Feminism is an advocacy for practise, its never a percentage of our society and should never be so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
