<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Scribblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T12:58:08+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sunil Kumar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engineering frowns!]]></title>
    <link href="http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/2014/01/18/engineering-frowns/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T14:14:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/2014/01/18/engineering-frowns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Right from the kindergarden days, I have had some great tutors. Mentors might be the right word to use considering the influence they had in my upbringing, my traits and for sure my education.</p>

<p><strong>John Aunty</strong>&ndash; My first KG teacher in New Models, Calcutta &ndash; her love and affection instilled confidence and faith in the most weepy child of the section feeling terrible amongst all those kids from North and Punjab. She taught me the basics of every vertical division of academics, ate her lunch with me and definitely gave me a feeling of my mother at school.</p>

<p><strong>Reena Madam</strong>&ndash; I had grown up a little, was probably in sixth but had arrived in a new school in a new town. Sreepuram EM school, ISC syllabus and all those blah blah and it was Reena Mam with her amazing charm and persona who helped me and a lot of other new kids settle down, teamed me up with some awesome new friends and made me feel assured.</p>

<p><strong>Pramode Sir</strong> &ndash; For sure, the best teacher I have had. Quite sure this would be the case with a whole lot of confused &amp; muddled up engineering brains. Had Pramode sir not been there &hellip; God knows!</p>

<p>Ok yes, so the title of this article doesn&rsquo;t suit with whatever I have written till now. <i>You could take this for a bit of polish on the surface. For what is going to follow could well give you a feeling that I am one of those disrespectful, ungrateful students to have caught your attention</i>. With whatever you have read, <strong>I wanted it to be crystal clear that I love, respect and will be grateful to my n number of tutors for lighting up the torch for me &amp; quite a few other thousands</strong>.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>Some educators, who are quick to say &quot;These students just don&#39;t want to learn”, should instead be saying &quot;I suck at my job”.</p>&mdash; Neil deGrasse Tyson (@neiltyson) <a href="https://twitter.com/neiltyson/statuses/420755108926730240">January 8, 2014</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://drones.sunilnkumar.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<br>


<p><strong>Incident -1</strong>: Happened back in my 3rd year or so. For some horror reason, I had to get into the dept. staff room. And Woila, I see 3 &ndash; 4 permanent lecturers of mine sitting in the staff room. Thats a rare sight in any case. Theres a discussion going on. Without question, I lend them my ears. The discussion is about paper valuation and the headaches it brought about. Count the number of pages, scribble over it and then put a pass mark &ndash; its a damn tedious task you know. Anyways one of my awesome tutors show up a real happy face with this statement &ndash; &lsquo;This guy has written like 3 pages for this 15 marks question but I intend to give him only a mere 3.&rsquo; The next goon in line follows it up with a nice shocker &ndash; &lsquo;HaHaHa&hellip;not a big deal. I gave only 15 marks for the whole paper I went through just now. Let him do it once more.&rsquo; and I got to know how examination papers were evaluated!</p>

<p><strong>Incident -2</strong>: One of my friend walks into the dept staff room (Yeah, so you get it now &ndash; thats the horror room :) ). Again probably in the 3rd year or so. The 1rst year university results have now been published and the guy in there is scrutinising all those results from the Calicut university website. His eyes gets stuck at the results of a girl (IT branch in some other college in our damn big university ) who seem to have scored high in almost all the subjects. There comes another shocker statement &ndash; &lsquo;If she is so studious, then how come she got into a self-financing college. Theres something murky. Its Ok, we will get her next year.&rsquo; For your info, a good number of examination papers were corrected in the aforesaid horror room.</p>

<p><strong>Incident -3</strong>: Semester 3: C lab examinations &amp; there are no external examiners. My friend completes his test, gets his output and comes out from the lab. Having done very well in our lab exams , we had good times.
3 -4 months, the results are announced. My friend is shocked to see his lab results. 30/100 after getting and thats after getting his output printed paper signed. I am sure he would have performed well in his viva too. So then what? No clues!</p>

<p>One of my classmates finds it difficult to pass her labs even after an unusual exemption of being offered with a chance to change her question. She leaves the lab weeping. A few minutes later, theres a discussion between our lecturers which in short could be summarised as a call being received from the girls mother and asking our &lsquo;kind-at-heart&rsquo; lecturers to do something about it. And yes, as you guessed it right, she just passed her labs.</p>

<p><strong>Incident -4</strong>: Me &amp; my friends( obviously, there were quite a few ) are in with back papers . As I had mentioned earlier, most of our examination papers are evaluated(supposedly) in our college itself, and thats not a myth. We decided to apply for a revaluation. Such a pacy university as ours is, it took more than a year for our revaluation results to show up. In the mean time, we wrote supplementary exams and got failed repeatedly. But once the revaluation results came up &ndash; god were they surprising? All of us passed, and some of them even got double of what they actually got prior to this. Such cases had become quite frequent then and we had serious plans of getting it noticed somewhere. But eventually, the feelings dried up and we just blew off.</p>

<p><strong>Incidents- 5,6,7,&mdash;&mdash;n</strong> that I can keep on listing here!</p>

<hr>




<br>


<p>I believe that words shouldn&rsquo;t be used to settle personal grudges. No way is anything above personal. I just wrote it down to reflect the mindsets of a <strong>filthy fraction of an awesome community</strong>. Of course we had great lecturers too. <strong>Vasudevan Sir, Shajeeb Sir, Raneeja mam, Prathibha Mam</strong> and quite a lot of others. But the ones I mentioned in those incidents are some of the most unprofessional and sadistic people I have met on earth. People who covered up 4 modules of a syllabus in 4 lectures and just took of to a malgudy planet after that. No one dared a question.</p>

<p>Might be a bit outrageous, but from what I have heard from my friends and my mother ( who happens to be a lecturer herself ) this is a greater problem. <strong>In every profession, the remuneration, rewards &amp; appraisals of an individual is dependent on the result or the outcome of the effort put in. If not, atleast by some standard metric which indicates performance</strong>. So if thats the case, whats the measurable here?</p>

<ul>
<li>Percentage of students passing out &ndash; For sure not, no one gives a damn about that and in any case thats not the most important thing.</li>
<li>Time spent in mentoring students to attain focus &ndash; What? There has to be something.</li>
</ul>


<p>I am not sure if any one has figured that out. My mother has told me quite well about the pathetic scenario in their college dept. My friends, people I know. No one. You don’t expect technical air in such a muddy pool. Sticking to my dept, there weren’t any knowledgeable consultant to guide to nor there was one to point out a reference. Graduates with 0 professional experience mentoring b.tech students in itself appears as a joke. If there are a few tutors worth remembering then they have to be the guest lecturers who despite of lacking professional knowledge had enough grit, intelligence and sincerity in their profession that we did benefit a lot from them. A few were good &amp; a few others were just Engineering horrors!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Through the commoner's eye]]></title>
    <link href="http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/2013/10/12/through-the-commoners-eye/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-12T19:04:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://drones.sunilnkumar.com/2013/10/12/through-the-commoners-eye</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am not quite sure if am ever the right one to pen this down. May be there are wiser men, the so called feminists, the politicians and even the professionals. However, I write this as a commoner of our nation, born and brought up here, as someone trying to get an ounce of the issues that we face as a society.</p>

<p>As a son, brother, husband or a father, as a friend or a colleague, we all love, respect and honour our women. As a citizen of this country, who has enjoyed the unlimited grant of freedom that this nation provides I want our women to be free and move around in the wear they choose and at a time thats convenient for them. I want and wish them to be safe, irrespective of whether its Delhi, Cochin, Cuttack or Imphal, regardless of whether its 2 in the afternoon or past midnight.</p>

<p><strong>Its precaution that matters more than the punishment.</strong></p>

<p>&lsquo;I want our women to be free, and travel safe&rsquo; &ndash; Thats the good part and thats over. Its no longer there. I am sorry if I pulled of the wrong words, but I mean every word of it. I love and fear the lives of the women connected with me, and the many millions who are not. As someone who is still young, I want my ladies to stay with me healthy and sound. Therefore to be very precise, I would keep communicating with her, try and stop her moving around alone at night, discourage her travel along with people whom she is not cent percent sure about and do keep a track on her where abouts when and where possible. On the flip side <i>I would never give a damn if she and her friends decide to get along and spend nights out in the beaches of pondicherry or Goa</i>. What I do and possibly want to do has nothing to do with a women&rsquo;s freedom, her rightful advocacy to have fun, and to be on par with me and the others who look like me. This is purely out of the love and the fear that a young guy has for the women in his life. I believe we are all born with enough logic to figure out a this from that, and its cardinal to remember that life matters more than the moment.</p>

<p>True, we have every right to demand severe punishment, may be model the arabs and the africans for the kind of severity and wildness they have in their system; casteration(chemical or else wise), stone them to death or let the public handle them, and whatever ways we could think off (which could well bring about positive results ). But then, we are talking about the punishment, the calvary and gehenna still continues for the loved ones. Along with the modification of laws for prosecuting the culprit, the right full measures for preventing such dreadful acts need to be materialized; and with equal priority.</p>

<p><strong>Isn&rsquo;t this connected to a few other stuffs?</strong></p>

<p>Why is that in our nation, we keep asking our girls to be home on time, not to travel late at night, not to attend her best friends marriage if she is in short of company? The answer is pretty simple, we understand that RAPE or molestation against women is not a stand alone challenge that we face as a society. Its just one out of the many connected nodes; the reasons of which are never perplex and hit straight in our eyes. Poverty, lack of proper education right from level one, a system where Co-education is never considered a mandatory to start with, the ceaseless issue of the ridiculous system of outcastes and the workmanships associated with them, lack of adequate security measures, and above all the availability of drugs and alcohol at rates lower than that of meals.</p>

<p>If you are a citizen who has lived the middle class, lower middle class life or even down from there, I hope you get these issues. You don&rsquo;t have to fume out your brains to get connected with this. Infographics tells me that South Africa has got more number of rape cases registered than any other country in the world ( The United States of America would be topping the list in some surveys as well! ). Now, I assume that this has nothing to do with the body and nature of the women out there &ndash; its all about the disastrous state of affairs that is well known to all and sundry. Lack of proper food, education and oppression by fellow beings could well and truly bring out the beast in a human, and when catalysed by alcohol could multiplicate and unleash into something as dirty and wild as could possibly happen. Again, even by the slightest of imaginations, this is never an offer of sympathy to these wicked acts. What they did was possibly the most cruel doing on earth and deserve appropriate punishment.</p>

<p><strong>May be, we could do something here!</strong></p>

<p>We do consider ourselves educated. In a nation like ours, it does mean a lot to each and every one of us, though never something that we could really boast of because we never had to sweat out for that. Our backgrounds, economical or social made sure that we grew up educated. Our parents and teachers who brought us up ensured that the moral values were infused in us in as much quantity and quality as science and history were taught to us. I still believe there&rsquo;s one big hole left though, and that for me is getting to your know opposite sex right from a childhood stage. Many believe that its high time co-education is considered a mandatory all the way till you complete your high school education. Myself being taught in mixed schools realize and understand the value of an environment where your opposite sex is never a matter of mystery for you.</p>

<p>Our society&rsquo;s perception of woman, and how woman themselves tackle situations is a matter of amplifying concern. I have seen all kinds of posts in social medias, from images and monster graphics to statuses on how each and every one of them would like to take it up with these barbarians. Fuming anger and outrage is most acceptable, but specific posts appears to be more of a mockery and generates disgust. Psuedo emotions always creeps up irritation. It seems like all, all those craps who have had the least respect for women, all those perverts who when offered with the most slender chance dig into a women&rsquo;s body in crowded transports as and where possible and all those wicked minds who associate terms like &lsquo;slut&rsquo; and &lsquo;whore&rsquo; to each and every women they come across, each and every one of them have got a say here. If you have done it in public transports with minds responsive, then what assurance that you won&rsquo;t do it in the dark when smitten up by alcohol?</p>

<p>In a state like Kerala, what honour do you see for women? A girl when seen with her boyfriend was manhandled by the public, a husband and wife were taken to the police station because they decided to have a breathe of fresh air on the beach sides, a women journalist alone at night was reportedly approached by at least 20 men, and what not? Its important to change this mindset to start with, and then may be we could sort out measures on what needs to be done with the ones caught red handed.</p>

<pre><code>                                            -   -   -       
</code></pre>

<p>Protests, marches and joint prayers in different corners of our nation ensure that we as a nation has not hit the mariana trench. May this be a collective effort which would bring in fruitful results, whether its about identifying the root causes, strengthening security measures and modifying the laws to enhance the mode of punishment. This requires the strength and support of each and every educated civilian in this nation. Feminism is an advocacy for practise, its never a percentage of our society and should never be so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
